Hello, everyone, and
welcome back to another great
lesson with English pod. My
name is Marco and I'm Erica.
Erica, today we have a
great intermediate lesson.
That's right. We've
got a lesson about love.
About love. And about apologizing. Okay.
Love and apologizing. They go together.
Yes, they do, especially if you
have a girlfriend or boyfriend, right?
That's true. Okay, so why don't we start
by looking at our vocabulary preview?
vocabulary preview. In
today's vocabulary preview,
we will learn two important
words from our dialogue.
What's the first word? Knock
over. Knock over. Knock over.
So that's a really simple one
when you knock something over.
You make it fall down. Make it fall down.
Yup. Speaking of knocking things over.
This morning, I knocked over
my coffee cup all over my desk.
Yeah, I saw that. You almost
ruined our lesson plan for today.
Yes, I did. It was
all over the place.
Okay, let's look at our
second word. Explode. Explode.
Explode. So when something
explodes, this is what happens.
Alright, that's pretty clear.
That's more than clear, I think.
So now we've looked at our two
vocabulary preview words for this
dialogue, and we are ready
to listen to it for the first time.
What's going on? Watch out!
Hey, what's where you're going?
Oh no, I'm so sorry. Are
you all right? I don't know.
I feel terrible. I really didn't mean to
knock you over. My tire just exploded and
I lost control of my bike. Really, it was
an accident. Please accept my apologies.
Just let me try to stand up.
Oh, wait a second.
You seem really familiar.
I think I know you're
from somewhere.
Yeah, that's right. I think
we've met somewhere before.
We met Aaron's place last
weekend. What a coincidence.
But anyway, I'm glad to see
you're not badly hurt, and I
should probably get going.
I've got a nine o'clock meeting.
But here's my number. Call me and
we'll exchange insurance information.
Oh, my ankle. I think it's broken.
You can't just leave me like this.
Are you calling an
ambulance? Nope. I'm canceling
my appointment so that
I can stay here with you.
I love happy ending. Such a
romantic dialogue. Yeah, this guy.
Oh my god, he is amazing. I
would love to meet a guy like that.
Like that, like crashing into you.
Maybe not like that.
Okay, well, I think it's time to
look at some of the language
in this dialogue. Let's start
with our language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Today, we
have three important words from
our dialogue that we will
learn for our language takeaway.
The first word is familiar.
Familiar. Familiar. This one I
think is a little bit hard to explain.
Yeah, so let's listen to some
examples on how we use familiar.
Example one.
Norman Clark. That name sounds familiar.
Where have I heard it before?
Example two. Do you
know where we are?
I have no idea. Nothing
looks familiar. I think we're lost.
Example three.
You look really familiar.
Did we go to high school together?
So when something's familiar, you think
you know it, but you're not exactly sure.
Exactly. Familiar. Okay.
Our next word is place. Place. Place.
Erin's place.
Exactly. So when we refer
to place, we refer to house.
Right. So I can say, hey, Marco, come
over to my place for dinner tonight.
Exactly. Or I could say, we're having
a party at my place tonight at eight.
You might ask someone,
how's your new place?
Right. How's your new apartment?
Exactly. That's a good one.
So place. It's a house.
Right. Our final word today is coincidence.
Coincidence. Coincidence.
So again, we have some great examples for
you to understand how we use coincidence.
Example one.
I'm going to New York this weekend.
What a coincidence. I am too.
Example two.
By coincidence, everyone
in the room was named Alex.
Example three.
We met by pure coincidence.
One day we ran into each
other on our bikes and
we've been together ever since.
A coincidence is something
that happens by chance, right?
Right. You didn't plan it.
It just happened.
Yeah. These funny little
things happen all the time.
I love it when these
coincidences happen.
Yeah, they're great. So
Erica, why don't you tell
us about a coincidence
that's happened to you?
Well, the other night I was
having dinner in a restaurant
and I looked up and I saw my
old professor from University.
It was such a coincidence because
here we are in Shanghai and I
see my professor from Canada
having dinner at the table next to me.
It was such a coincidence.
That is a coincidence.
Yeah. Or has it ever
happened to you that you're
thinking of someone
and that person calls you?
That happens all the time.
That's a coincidence. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Okay. So now that we have
learned these three language takeaway words,
we can listen to our dialogue a second
time, but this time it's going to be slower.
Hey, watch where you're going.
Oh, no. I'm so sorry. Are you all right?
Oh, I don't know.
I feel terrible. I didn't
mean to knock you over.
My tire just exploded and
I lost control of my bike.
Really? It was an accident.
Please accept my apologies.
Just let me try to stand up.
Oh, wait a second.
You seem really familiar.
I think I know you from somewhere.
Yeah. I think we have met somewhere before.
That's right. We met at Aaron's
place last weekend. What a coincidence.
But anyway, I'm glad to see that you're not
badly hurt and I should probably get going.
I have a nine o'clock meeting.
But here's my number. Call me and
we'll exchange insurance information.
Ouch. My ankle. I think it's broken.
You can't just leave me like this.
Are you calling an ambulance?
No. I'm canceling my appointment
so that I can stay here with you.
Well, that was much clearer, wasn't it?
Yes. That was clear and this
brings us to fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
In today's fluency builder, we're going
to show you different ways of apologizing.
It's so important to be able
to apologize well and fluently.
Exactly. And you also want to say
something different from, I'm sorry.
Right. So that's what we're
going to show you today.
We heard some great expressions for, I'm
sorry, in the dialogue. Let's listen now.
I'm so sorry. I feel terrible.
Please accept my apologies.
Yeah, I feel terrible.
I say this one all the time.
Yeah, it's a great way of saying I'm sorry.
Now also, if you want to
say I'm sorry, you also want
to tell the person that
you made a mistake, right?
That's true. And we
did hear some wonderful
expressions for, I made
a mistake in this dialogue.
I didn't mean to knock you over.
It was an accident.
Well, I didn't mean to knock
my coffee cup over this morning.
Exactly.
It was an accident.
It was.
Not on purpose, right?
Or so you think.
Okay.
So all of these phrases
are really useful and great
for apologizing and telling
someone you made a mistake.
Well, it's time for us to listen
to our dialogue at third time.
This time it'll be at its
normal speed, and I think
you'll be able to
understand a little bit better.
Wow, what's going on?
Watch out!
Hey, what's where you're going?
Oh no, I'm so sorry.
Are you all right?
Oh, I don't know.
I feel terrible.
I really didn't mean to knock you over.
My tires exploded and
I lost control of my bike.
Really, it was an accident.
Please accept my apologies.
Just let me try to stand up.
Oh, wait a second.
You seem really familiar.
I think I know you're from somewhere.
Yeah, that's right.
I think we've met somewhere before.
We met Aaron's place last weekend.
What a coincidence.
But anyway, I'm glad to see you're not
badly hurt and I should probably get going.
I've got a nine o'clock meeting.
But here's my number.
Call me and we'll exchange
insurance information.
Oh, my ankle.
I think it's broken.
You can't just leave me like this.
Are you calling an ambulance?
Nope. I'm canceling my appointment
so that I can stay here with you.
Great dialogue and great music, right?
Wonderful music.
Who picked that, Marco?
Of course.
Me.
I'm a romantic type.
I love romantic music.
Really?
Yes.
Well, speaking of a romantic type,
do you believe in love at first sight?
I kind of do.
I'd like to believe it.
Yeah, well, that surprises me.
Well, I think the first time
that you see someone,
it impresses you some way and
you feel attracted to that person.
Really?
Yeah.
At least it's the first feeling
that you get that makes you
want to talk to that person
or get to know that person.
I am the exact opposite, really.
When I see somebody for the first
time, my first impression is always wrong.
Okay.
So if I see someone and I like them at the
beginning, in three weeks I'll hate them.
And if I see someone
and I don't like them when
I first meet them, I'll
be their best friend.
Yeah, yeah.
So love at first sight doesn't work for me.
I'm sure that our listeners have
some stories at love at first sight.
Maybe they've met their wives
or their boyfriends in this way.
I'd like to hear about it.
Me too.
And if anybody knows the
name of the songs we used,
also be sure to post it
on the discussion board.
That's right.
Our challenge for this.
Our challenge for this lesson.
Yeah.
So that's all for today, everyone.
But be sure to go to our
website at englishpot.com.
And as we said, leave all
your comments, your stories,
and see if you know the name of the songs.
Okay.
Well, thanks for listening, everyone.
And until next time, goodbye.
Bye.